TEJAS KANJI

Software Development Engineer

+91 90829 98315 🔀 <u>tejas5225@gmail.com</u>

Mumbai, India 🖶 https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejas-kanji/

[PortFolio] https://www.crio.do/learn/portfolio/tejas5225/

Profile

Software Engineer with 1.5 years of Work Experience in delivering end-to-end solutions. Willing to work with large teams and always motivated to develop new skills and evolve. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills to deliver state of the art software from scratch.

Skills

Programming Languages Python, Java, JavaScript, (Familiar) C / C++

Database Skills Postgres SQL, MySQL, SQLITE, SQL Alchemy ORM, Django ORM,

MongoDB Atlas

Cloud Frameworks AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform

Front End HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, React, Material UI

Back End Django REST Framework, ExpressJS, PyQT / PySide 6 (Desktop)

Extras DSA, LLD, DEV-OOPS, TDD, Docker

Work Experience

Software Engineer

dMACQ Software PVT LTD JUN 2021 – OCT 2022

Mumbai, India

Worked as a key python developer involved with multiple teams and international clients

- Implement the end-to-end solution withing timeline
- increased performance of applications by 50% using DSA
- Made Reusable Code with DEV-OOP Concepts
- Implemented ORM to reduce source code by 60%
- Worked with teams of size 3-10, including clients
- Delivered Robust Desktop and Web Applications Demo in 1 week

Tech Stack: Python, HTML, CSS, Google Vision, ML, OpenCV, OCR, Django REST, PyQT, PySide, Pandas, RPA, SQLAlchemy ORM, Git

Python Developer Intern

dMACQ Software PVT LTD FEB 2021 – MAY 2021

Mumbai, India

- Learned Basic RPA Workflow
- Worked on following: Document Automation, Text Extraction
- Learned to extract text from documents and images via OCRs

Tech Stack: Python, HTML, CSS, ML, OpenCV, Pandas

Crio Fellowship Projects

QTripDynamic Aug 2022

https://lord-tejas-qtripdynamic.netlify.app/ **QTripDynamic** is a travel website aimed at travellers looking for a multitude of adventures in different cities.

- Created web pages using HTML and CSS and made them dynamic using JavaScript
- Improved UX with multi-select filters, image carousels
- Utilized localStorage to persist user preferences at client-side

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, DOM Manipulation, JSON, REST, cURL, Heroku, Netlify

OKart

Oct 2022

https://tejas-kanji-qkartfrontend.netlify.app/ **QKart** is an e-commerce application offering a variety of products for customers to choose from.

- Implemented core logic for authentication, shopping cart, checkout
- Improved UI by adding responsive design with react
- Utilized REST APIs to dynamically load and render data served by the backend server

Tech Stack: React Hooks, Forms, Controlled Components, REST, JSON, Error Handling, Conditional Rendering, LIFECYCLE METHODS, Material UI, Responsive Design, Material UI, Debouncing, Netlify, Heroku

XFlix Feb 2023

https://tejas-kanji-xflixreact.netlify.app/ **Xflix** is a one repo application with both frontend and backend in one place, Clone like famous Netflix

- Built XBoard frontend using React, Material UI
- Built Custom Components from scratch using react hooks
- Made backend API using Postman MOCK Server and express
- Deployed the Database on MongoDB Atlas

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, React, Material UI, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Postman, MongoDB Atlas, Render, Netlify

Education

Bachelors in Computer Applications

Amrita University 🕈 Coimbatore, India

JUL 2021 - PRESENT Current CGPA: 9.04

HSC (12th Grade)

Patuck College Of Science ♥ Mumbai, India Jul 2017 - Mar 2019

Computer Science (69 %)

Certifications & Achievements

- Intro to Machine Learning With TensorFlow (Udacity)
- Python Master Course (Udemy)
- Algorithmic Toolbox (Coursera)
- MERN Full Stack Developer Course (Crio.do)
- Fellowship Advance DSA, DEV-OOP, LLD, HLD, DevOps (Crio.do)
- Check Out my GitHub Projects! https://github.com/LordTejas

Competitive Coding Profile

Solved 500+ Problems across all these platforms:

- https://www.hackerrank.com/lord-tejas Hackerrank
- https://leetcode.com/LordTejas/ LeetCode
- Ranked Top 5000 World Rank in 2020 in Python Implementation Rankings (Hackerank)
- Has 5 Star Badges in Python, Java, C++, SQL, Regex, etc. (Hackerrank)